<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>leadership on A Blog</title>
    <link>/tags/leadership/</link>
    <description>Recent content in leadership on A Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 May 2023 06:49:57 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/leadership/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Take the Easy Way</title>
      <link>/2023/05/19/take-the-easy-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2023 06:49:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2023/05/19/take-the-easy-way/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m not a morning person, but in the household division of labor, I&amp;rsquo;m the one responsible for getting the kids up and out to school in the morning. It&amp;rsquo;s not ideal. I&amp;rsquo;m not happily awake or fully caffeinated, and I just want the kids to comply the first time I tell them to get their shoes on. When we&amp;rsquo;re behind schedule getting out the door, I can lose my patience. My voice gets louder, and there&amp;rsquo;s palpable stress because &amp;ldquo;we&amp;rsquo;re going to be late!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flow Like Water</title>
      <link>/2020/03/16/flow-like-water/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 06:49:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/03/16/flow-like-water/</guid>
      <description>A rip current is a powerful flow that can drag an unsuspecting swimmer out to sea. When visiting a beach with rip currents, you&amp;rsquo;re told that if you get caught in one, you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t try to swim back toward the beach, against the current&amp;mdash;it&amp;rsquo;s too strong. Instead, you should swim parallel to the beach to get out of the current, and then you can get back to shore more easily.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To Err Is Human; To Ignore, Divine</title>
      <link>/2019/07/17/to-err-is-human-to-ignore-divine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2019 06:49:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/07/17/to-err-is-human-to-ignore-divine/</guid>
      <description>One of the great things about leading a software project is the sense of ownership over what you and your team are creating. Your mind is buzzing with the big picture of what your project can do and will be able to do. You also sweat the details, and particularly if you&amp;rsquo;ve been with it from the beginning, you have unrivaled breadth and depth of knowledge about the project.
So, when someone&amp;mdash;a user or new team member, for example&amp;mdash;has a question, you know the answer.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
