<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>A Blog</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on A Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2017 21:49:57 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>7 Hard Testing Problems Made Easy By httptest</title>
      <link>/2017/06/21/7-hard-testing-problems-made-easy-by-httptest/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2017 21:49:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/06/21/7-hard-testing-problems-made-easy-by-httptest/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a big advocate of testing and test automation, both on the team I lead and in my own projects. Tests provide valuable evidence that your code works. Without tests, you&amp;rsquo;re engaging in faith-based development: you believe your code works because you believe in your own infallibility as a coder. Theology aside, as a practical matter, tests are liberating because they allow you to modify and extend your code without fear of breaking existing functionality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Blogdown Site with Travis-CI</title>
      <link>/2017/06/01/building-a-blogdown-site-with-travis-ci/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 21:49:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/06/01/building-a-blogdown-site-with-travis-ci/</guid>
      <description>Over on the Crunch.io dev blog, I wrote about how we used Travis-CI to automate the building of our various static sites. I thought I’d do the same for my personal blog, though with one twist: using R and the blogdown package on top of Hugo.
This blogdown GitHub issue pointed to Yihui’s guide to building bookdown projects on Travis, as well as a project that had adapted that flow for blogdown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This Is a Blog</title>
      <link>/2017/05/22/this-is-a-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 21:11:48 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/05/22/this-is-a-blog/</guid>
      <description>This page left intentionally blank.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 21:48:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi. I&amp;rsquo;m a recovering academic currently working as product manager and engineering leader. I still like to code and play with data when I can.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>