<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>A Blog</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on A Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2017 16:49:57 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Down with pkgdown</title>
      <link>/2017/11/21/getting-down-with-pkgdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2017 16:49:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/11/21/getting-down-with-pkgdown/</guid>
      <description>pkgdown is an incredibly powerful tool for building beautiful websites for R packages. With pkgdown and services like GitHub Pages, deploying a package website is so simple and straightforward that I&amp;rsquo;m starting to see it as an essential part of writing a package. What&amp;rsquo;s more, I&amp;rsquo;ve found that the act of preparing a package website has led me to improve the package itself, particularly the readability and usefulness of its documentation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>httptest 2.3.2 Released</title>
      <link>/2017/10/20/httptest-2.3.2-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2017 09:00:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/10/20/httptest-2.3.2-released/</guid>
      <description>The 2.3.2 release of httptest has just been published on CRAN. Since the 2.0.0 release in June, several key additions have been made. See the NEWS for the full list. If you follow those links, you&amp;rsquo;ll see the first new &amp;ldquo;feature&amp;rdquo;: httptest now has a proper website, using the pkgdown site generator!
In terms of functionality, the biggest change has been the addition of a framework for &amp;ldquo;redacting&amp;rdquo;, or removing sensitive information like tokens and ids from test fixtures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One-Hour Package</title>
      <link>/2017/08/11/one-hour-package/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2017 16:49:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/08/11/one-hour-package/</guid>
      <description>At Crunch, I occasionally pick up small coding projects to help with project management. Recently, I wanted a way to get automated reporting on our open issues in Usersnap, a service embedded in our web application that allows users to report bugs from within the app. My thought was to set up a cron job to report daily summaries in our Slack channel on things like the number of reports created, resolved, and so on, so that we could make sure that bug reports were being addressed quickly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Should You Add a Package Dependency?</title>
      <link>/2017/08/05/should-you-add-a-package-dependency/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2017 21:49:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/08/05/should-you-add-a-package-dependency/</guid>
      <description>At Crunch, we’ve recently hired an “R Team” to build out our package offerings beyond what I could write in my spare time. It’s been great to have more resources to dedicate to our R tools, and it’s been particularly fun for me because now I get to have package design debates with other smart humans, not just inside my head.
In one such debate, we discussed when it was appropriate to add a new dependency to a package.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Better Management Through Code</title>
      <link>/2017/07/04/better-management-through-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2017 16:49:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/07/04/better-management-through-code/</guid>
      <description>At Crunch, I lead both engineering and product management. Over the last few years, what that entails has changed greatly. How I spent my day when we were getting started, with a team of four developers and zero users, is very different from how I spend my time now with 16 on the team and thousands of users around the world. In fact, my day-to-day has evolved through several phases as we&amp;rsquo;ve grown, and each phase has come with its own challenges and learning opportunities—or rather, challenges that are learning opportunities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>7 Hard Testing Problems Made Easy By httptest</title>
      <link>/2017/06/21/7-hard-testing-problems-made-easy-by-httptest/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2017 21:49:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/06/21/7-hard-testing-problems-made-easy-by-httptest/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a big advocate of testing and test automation, both on the team I lead and in my own projects. Tests provide valuable evidence that your code works. Without tests, you&amp;rsquo;re engaging in faith-based development: you believe your code works because you believe in your own infallibility as a coder. Theology aside, as a practical matter, tests are liberating because they allow you to modify and extend your code without fear of breaking existing functionality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Blogdown Site with Travis-CI</title>
      <link>/2017/06/01/building-a-blogdown-site-with-travis-ci/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 21:49:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/06/01/building-a-blogdown-site-with-travis-ci/</guid>
      <description>Over on the Crunch.io dev blog, I wrote about how we used Travis-CI to automate the building of our various static sites. I thought I’d do the same for my personal blog, though with one twist: using R and the blogdown package on top of Hugo.
This blogdown GitHub issue pointed to Yihui’s guide to building bookdown projects on Travis, as well as a project that had adapted that flow for blogdown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This Is a Blog</title>
      <link>/2017/05/22/this-is-a-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 21:11:48 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/05/22/this-is-a-blog/</guid>
      <description>This page left intentionally blank.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 21:48:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi. I&amp;rsquo;m a recovering academic currently working as product manager and engineering leader. I still like to code and play with data when I can.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>