<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on A Blog</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on A Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 06:49:57 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Flow Like Water</title>
      <link>/2020/03/16/flow-like-water/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 06:49:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/03/16/flow-like-water/</guid>
      <description>A rip current is a powerful flow that can drag an unsuspecting swimmer out to sea. When visiting a beach with rip currents, you&amp;rsquo;re told that if you get caught in one, you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t try to swim back toward the beach, against the current&amp;mdash;it&amp;rsquo;s too strong. Instead, you should swim parallel to the beach to get out of the current, and then you can get back to shore more easily.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To Err Is Human; To Ignore, Divine</title>
      <link>/2019/07/17/to-err-is-human-to-ignore-divine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2019 06:49:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/07/17/to-err-is-human-to-ignore-divine/</guid>
      <description>One of the great things about leading a software project is the sense of ownership over what you and your team are creating. Your mind is buzzing with the big picture of what your project can do and will be able to do. You also sweat the details, and particularly if you&amp;rsquo;ve been with it from the beginning, you have unrivaled breadth and depth of knowledge about the project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing Docs Is Better Than Having Docs</title>
      <link>/2019/02/17/writing-docs-is-better-than-having-docs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2019 16:49:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/02/17/writing-docs-is-better-than-having-docs/</guid>
      <description>When interviewing developers at Crunch, we sometimes do a live coding exercise using a JavaScript data visualization library. It&amp;rsquo;s basic, and we don&amp;rsquo;t assume any prior knowledge of the library. To start, we tell the candidate that they can use the full internet to help them solve the problem (we&amp;rsquo;re trying to simulate real working conditions, after all), and by the way, this library has excellent documentation.
It&amp;rsquo;s about 50-50 the candidates that ever open the docs&amp;mdash;the other half go straight to Stack Overflow to look for code to copy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing Logs with AWS Athena</title>
      <link>/2019/02/08/analyzing-logs-with-aws-athena/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2019 16:49:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/02/08/analyzing-logs-with-aws-athena/</guid>
      <description>This week, I wanted to analyze some web traffic patterns back over several years. For contemporary analysis, we sync the last couple of months of load balancer (AWS ELB) log files from S3 to a EC2 instance, and I&amp;rsquo;ve written some tools in R to query them using dplyr methods. The elbr R package I wrote does some clever things to take advantage of the directory structure for fast filtering by date, and it supports parallelized reading and querying of the files, among other optimizations, so it&amp;rsquo;s reasonably fast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The S-Curve</title>
      <link>/2019/01/03/the-s-curve/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 16:49:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/01/03/the-s-curve/</guid>
      <description>At Crunch, we&amp;rsquo;ve built up our product over the span of six years, and what we&amp;rsquo;ve built helps a lot of people analyze their data quickly and painlessly. As ever, our ambitions are great and we want to build more. Sometimes this requires changing data contracts and APIs, and that poses an additional challenge: not only do we have to design a good solution to our users&amp;rsquo; problems, we have to transition to it with minimal disruption.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>httptest 3.2.0 Released</title>
      <link>/2018/11/11/httptest-3.2.0-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Nov 2018 09:00:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/11/11/httptest-3.2.0-released/</guid>
      <description>The 3.2.0 release of httptest is now on CRAN. This is a minor release with several enhancements suggested by package users. Details can be found in the release notes.
A few of the changes improve the behavior of httptest in interactive use. There is one new function, use_httptest(), which configures your package to use httptest when you&amp;rsquo;re setting it up.
Thanks to everyone who filed issues and submitted pull requests. Included in this release are contributions from and improvements prompted by GitHub users brooklynbagel, jameslamb, jjankowiak, npelikan, and ramiromagno.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talk Slides Now Available</title>
      <link>/2018/08/13/talk-slides-now-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 12:49:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/08/13/talk-slides-now-available/</guid>
      <description>In putting up the slides for the talk I gave at last week&amp;rsquo;s Bay Area R meetup, I figured it would be good to dig up the slides from previous talks and post them here too. (In fact, I linked to one of them in the slides from last week.) So, there&amp;rsquo;s now a &amp;ldquo;Talks&amp;rdquo; section of the site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Against Technical Debt</title>
      <link>/2018/07/08/against-technical-debt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2018 21:49:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/07/08/against-technical-debt/</guid>
      <description>As a product owner and development leader, I often hear that &amp;ldquo;we have to pay our technical debt&amp;rdquo; in order to proceed with our product plan. As the metaphor goes, when you choose to take shortcuts now, you incur a debt that you&amp;rsquo;ll eventually have to repay with interest. The implication when a developer raises it is that those interest payments are too high and are preventing us from moving forward as effectively as we should.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Turbocharging &#39;readr&#39;</title>
      <link>/2018/04/25/turbocharging-readr/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Apr 2018 21:49:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/04/25/turbocharging-readr/</guid>
      <description>Recently I analyzed some web traffic for my team at an all-hands meetup. I suspected there were some misconceptions about the frequency of certain kinds of requests, and that some basic descriptive statistics could help.
Whenever I start an analysis like this, I also think about how to make it easier to repeat it. If the question is interesting enough to merit analysis now, it will probably be interesting next month too&amp;mdash;particularly if it reveals things we want to improve.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back to the Future</title>
      <link>/2018/02/01/back-to-the-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 16:49:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/02/01/back-to-the-future/</guid>
      <description>When you submit a package update to CRAN, they ask you to check some boxes confirming that you&amp;rsquo;ve done your due diligence on your submission: that it passes its checks. One confirmation is that you&amp;rsquo;ve addressed any failures on the CRAN package check page, which looks like this.
  Hey, all passing today!   This page is a window into one of the key features of CRAN: it runs continuous-integration tests of your package against multiple versions of R, on multiple operating systems, with the current version of your dependencies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrating &#39;pkgdown&#39; with Your Personal Website</title>
      <link>/2017/12/18/integrating-pkgdown-with-your-personal-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2017 16:49:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/12/18/integrating-pkgdown-with-your-personal-website/</guid>
      <description>Publishing a website for your R package is simple with pkgdown. As I recently discussed, you can build a basic site and host it on GitHub Pages with just a handful of commands and clicks.
That&amp;rsquo;s a great start, but why stop there? If you have a personal website or blog, it would be nice to have your package page mesh with it&amp;mdash;that is, it should fit with your &amp;ldquo;brand&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Down with pkgdown</title>
      <link>/2017/11/21/getting-down-with-pkgdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2017 16:49:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/11/21/getting-down-with-pkgdown/</guid>
      <description>pkgdown is an incredibly powerful tool for building beautiful websites for R packages. With pkgdown and services like GitHub Pages, deploying a package website is so simple and straightforward that I&amp;rsquo;m starting to see it as an essential part of writing a package. What&amp;rsquo;s more, I&amp;rsquo;ve found that the act of preparing a package website has led me to improve the package itself, particularly the readability and usefulness of its documentation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>httptest 2.3.2 Released</title>
      <link>/2017/10/20/httptest-2.3.2-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2017 09:00:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/10/20/httptest-2.3.2-released/</guid>
      <description>The 2.3.2 release of httptest has just been published on CRAN. Since the 2.0.0 release in June, several key additions have been made. See the NEWS for the full list. If you follow those links, you&amp;rsquo;ll see the first new &amp;ldquo;feature&amp;rdquo;: httptest now has a proper website, using the pkgdown site generator!
In terms of functionality, the biggest change has been the addition of a framework for &amp;ldquo;redacting&amp;rdquo;, or removing sensitive information like tokens and ids from test fixtures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One-Hour Package</title>
      <link>/2017/08/11/one-hour-package/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2017 16:49:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/08/11/one-hour-package/</guid>
      <description>At Crunch, I occasionally pick up small coding projects to help with project management. Recently, I wanted a way to get automated reporting on our open issues in Usersnap, a service embedded in our web application that allows users to report bugs from within the app. My thought was to set up a cron job to report daily summaries in our Slack channel on things like the number of reports created, resolved, and so on, so that we could make sure that bug reports were being addressed quickly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Should You Add a Package Dependency?</title>
      <link>/2017/08/05/should-you-add-a-package-dependency/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2017 21:49:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/08/05/should-you-add-a-package-dependency/</guid>
      <description>At Crunch, we’ve recently hired an “R Team” to build out our package offerings beyond what I could write in my spare time. It’s been great to have more resources to dedicate to our R tools, and it’s been particularly fun for me because now I get to have package design debates with other smart humans, not just inside my head.
In one such debate, we discussed when it was appropriate to add a new dependency to a package.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Better Management Through Code</title>
      <link>/2017/07/04/better-management-through-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2017 16:49:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/07/04/better-management-through-code/</guid>
      <description>At Crunch, I lead both engineering and product management. Over the last few years, what that entails has changed greatly. How I spent my day when we were getting started, with a team of four developers and zero users, is very different from how I spend my time now with 16 on the team and thousands of users around the world. In fact, my day-to-day has evolved through several phases as we&amp;rsquo;ve grown, and each phase has come with its own challenges and learning opportunities&amp;mdash;or rather, challenges that are learning opportunities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>7 Hard Testing Problems Made Easy By httptest</title>
      <link>/2017/06/21/7-hard-testing-problems-made-easy-by-httptest/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2017 21:49:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/06/21/7-hard-testing-problems-made-easy-by-httptest/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a big advocate of testing and test automation, both on the team I lead and in my own projects. Tests provide valuable evidence that your code works. Without tests, you&amp;rsquo;re engaging in faith-based development: you believe your code works because you believe in your own infallibility as a coder. Theology aside, as a practical matter, tests are liberating because they allow you to modify and extend your code without fear of breaking existing functionality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Blogdown Site with Travis-CI</title>
      <link>/2017/06/01/building-a-blogdown-site-with-travis-ci/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 21:49:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/06/01/building-a-blogdown-site-with-travis-ci/</guid>
      <description>Over on the Crunch.io dev blog, I wrote about how we used Travis-CI to automate the building of our various static sites. I thought I’d do the same for my personal blog, though with one twist: using R and the blogdown package on top of Hugo.
This blogdown GitHub issue pointed to Yihui’s guide to building bookdown projects on Travis, as well as a project that had adapted that flow for blogdown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This Is a Blog</title>
      <link>/2017/05/22/this-is-a-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 21:11:48 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/05/22/this-is-a-blog/</guid>
      <description>This page left intentionally blank.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>