<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Management on A Blog</title>
    <link>/categories/management/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Management on A Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 06:49:57 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/categories/management/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Obey the Timer</title>
      <link>/2023/05/30/obey-the-timer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 06:49:57 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/2023/05/30/obey-the-timer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When my kids were little, we spent lots of time at the playground. The hardest part was when it was time to leave: they were having fun and didn&amp;rsquo;t want to go. When you have to drag a screaming kid off the play structure, it&amp;rsquo;s unpleasant for everyone, so we needed a way to get them to come willingly.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The trick we landed on was to give them a 5-minute warning that we&amp;rsquo;re going to leave, then set a timer on the phone. When the timer goes off, it&amp;rsquo;s time to go. (Little kids have no concept of time, so it doesn&amp;rsquo;t even need to be five minutes, for the record.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Take the Easy Way</title>
      <link>/2023/05/19/take-the-easy-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2023 06:49:57 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>/2023/05/19/take-the-easy-way/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not a morning person, but in the household division of labor, I&amp;rsquo;m the one responsible for getting the kids up and out to school in the morning. It&amp;rsquo;s not ideal. I&amp;rsquo;m not happily awake or fully caffeinated, and I just want the kids to comply the first time I tell them to get their shoes on. When we&amp;rsquo;re behind schedule getting out the door, I can lose my patience. My voice gets louder, and there&amp;rsquo;s palpable stress because &amp;ldquo;we&amp;rsquo;re going to be late!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Flow Like Water</title>
      <link>/2020/03/16/flow-like-water/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 06:49:57 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>/2020/03/16/flow-like-water/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A rip current is a powerful flow that can drag an unsuspecting swimmer out to sea. When visiting a beach with rip currents, you&amp;rsquo;re told that if you get caught in one, you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t try to swim back toward the beach, against the current&amp;mdash;it&amp;rsquo;s too strong. Instead, you should swim parallel to the beach to get out of the current, and then you can get back to shore more easily.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>To Err Is Human; To Ignore, Divine</title>
      <link>/2019/07/17/to-err-is-human-to-ignore-divine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2019 06:49:57 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>/2019/07/17/to-err-is-human-to-ignore-divine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the great things about leading a software project is the sense of ownership over what you and your team are creating. Your mind is buzzing with the big picture of what your project can do and will be able to do. You also sweat the details, and particularly if you&amp;rsquo;ve been with it from the beginning, you have unrivaled breadth and depth of knowledge about the project.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So, when someone&amp;mdash;a user or new team member, for example&amp;mdash;has a question, you know the answer. And when they make what seems like a naive proposal, you know why they&amp;rsquo;re wrong. It triggers the &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://xkcd.com/386/&#34;&gt;someone is wrong on the internet&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; sense, and you feel compelled to jump in and nip that wrongness in the bud.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The S-Curve</title>
      <link>/2019/01/03/the-s-curve/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 16:49:57 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>/2019/01/03/the-s-curve/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At &lt;a href=&#34;https://crunch.io/&#34;&gt;Crunch&lt;/a&gt;, we&amp;rsquo;ve built up our product over the span of six years, and what we&amp;rsquo;ve built helps a lot of people analyze their data quickly and painlessly. As ever, our ambitions are great and we want to build more. Sometimes this requires changing data contracts and APIs, and that poses an additional challenge: not only do we have to design a good solution to our users&amp;rsquo; problems, we have to transition to it with minimal disruption.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Against Technical Debt</title>
      <link>/2018/07/08/against-technical-debt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2018 21:49:57 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>/2018/07/08/against-technical-debt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a product owner and development leader, I often hear that &amp;ldquo;we have to pay our technical debt&amp;rdquo; in order to proceed with our product plan. As the metaphor goes, when you choose to take shortcuts now, you incur a debt that you&amp;rsquo;ll eventually have to repay with interest. The implication when a developer raises it is that those interest payments are too high and are preventing us from moving forward as effectively as we should.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Better Management Through Code</title>
      <link>/2017/07/04/better-management-through-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2017 16:49:57 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>/2017/07/04/better-management-through-code/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At &lt;a href=&#34;https://crunch.io/&#34;&gt;Crunch&lt;/a&gt;, I lead both engineering and product management. Over the last few years, what that entails has changed greatly. How I spent my day when we were getting started, with a team of four developers and zero users, is very different from how I spend my time now with 16 on the team and thousands of users around the world. In fact, my day-to-day has evolved through several phases as we&amp;rsquo;ve grown, and each phase has come with its own challenges and learning opportunities&amp;mdash;or rather, challenges that are learning opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
