<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Management on A Blog</title>
    <link>/tags/management/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Management on A Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2019 06:49:57 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/management/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>To Err Is Human; To Ignore, Divine</title>
      <link>/2019/07/17/to-err-is-human-to-ignore-divine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2019 06:49:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/07/17/to-err-is-human-to-ignore-divine/</guid>
      <description>One of the great things about leading a software project is the sense of ownership over what you and your team are creating. Your mind is buzzing with the big picture of what your project can do and will be able to do. You also sweat the details, and particularly if you&amp;rsquo;ve been with it from the beginning, you have unrivaled breadth and depth of knowledge about the project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The S-Curve</title>
      <link>/2019/01/03/the-s-curve/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 16:49:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/01/03/the-s-curve/</guid>
      <description>At Crunch, we&amp;rsquo;ve built up our product over the span of six years, and what we&amp;rsquo;ve built helps a lot of people analyze their data quickly and painlessly. As ever, our ambitions are great and we want to build more. Sometimes this requires changing data contracts and APIs, and that poses an additional challenge: not only do we have to design a good solution to our users&amp;rsquo; problems, we have to transition to it with minimal disruption.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Better Management Through Code</title>
      <link>/2017/07/04/better-management-through-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2017 16:49:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/07/04/better-management-through-code/</guid>
      <description>At Crunch, I lead both engineering and product management. Over the last few years, what that entails has changed greatly. How I spent my day when we were getting started, with a team of four developers and zero users, is very different from how I spend my time now with 16 on the team and thousands of users around the world. In fact, my day-to-day has evolved through several phases as we&amp;rsquo;ve grown, and each phase has come with its own challenges and learning opportunities&amp;mdash;or rather, challenges that are learning opportunities.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>